# Praveensankar M

# M.Tech - Student



praveensankar1995@gmail.com Homepage: https://praveen.xyz/

Google Scholar:

https://scholar.google.co.in/citations?user=o

yTr15UAAAAJ&hl=en&authuser=1

ORCID:

https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3614-5722

# **BIO**

I am a second-year masters student studying at National Institute of Technology Puducherry, India. I have worked on blockchain technology and Named Data Networking. In Blockchain, I have experience in Hyperledger fabric. I have developed an Intrusion Detection System for NDN-Based VANET. I have developed a public key authenticated encryption scheme based on lattice cryptography for my masters' thesis. My research interests are in Blockchain, Cryptography, Lattice Cryptography, Cyber Security and Network Security.

#### **Area of Interest**

- Blockchain
- Lattice Cryptography
- Network Security

Cryptography

#### **EDUCATION**

## M.Tech. - Computer Science and Engineering

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal July 2018 - June 2020

CGPA - 9.77 / 10 ( Class Topper)

#### **B.E.** - Computer Science and Engineering

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore July 2012 - May 2016

CGPA - 7.69 / 10

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Book Chapter**

Ravi, Chandrasekar and Praveensankar Manimaran. "Introduction of Blockchain and Usage of Blockchain in Internet of Things." *Transforming Businesses With Bitcoin Mining and Blockchain Applications*. IGI Global, 2020. 1-15. Web. 18 Oct. 2019. doi:10.4018/978-1-7998-0186-3.ch001

https://www.igi-global.com/chapter/introduction-of-blockchain-and-usage-of-blockchain-in-interne t-of-things/238356

#### Conference

- Praveensankar Manimaran and P. Arun Raj Kumar, "NDNIDS: An Intrusion Detection System for NDN Based VANET," VTC2020-Spring Recent Results and Workshops, Antwerp, Belgium.(Accepted)
- P. Manimaran and R. Dhanalakshmi, "Blockchain-Based Smart Contract for E-Bidding System," 2019 2nd International Conference on Intelligent Communication and Computational Techniques (ICCT), Jaipur, India, 2019, pp. 55-59. doi: 10.1109/ICCT46177.2019.8969042.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8969042

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Summer Research Intern**

National Institute of Technology Calicut, Kozhikode May 2019 - July 2019

- Studied about Software Defined Networking
- Worked with mininet simulator to simulator SDN environment
- Studied the architecture of the Named Data Networking and usage of NDN in VANET
- Designed and developed Intrusion Detection System for NDN Based VANET

#### **Software Engineer**

Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore July 2016 - March 2017

- Worked on the web development
- Language C#, Javascript, Web framework ASP.NET MVC, backend technology -ASP.NET, frontend technology - Jquery and AngularJS, database - Microsoft SQL Server
- Developed POC application for IT Resource Management
- Worked on web development for British Telecommunications through Accolite

## **Software Engineer Intern**

Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore January 2016 - April 2016

- Worked on the web development
- Language C#, Javascript, Web framework ASP.NET MVC, backend technology -ASP.NET, frontend technology - Jquery and AngularJS, database - Microsoft SQL Server
- Learned about web development in general and studied ASP.NET and Basic javascript for developing websites
- Studied about 3 Layer architecture in ASP.NET

# **Projects**

# **Android Application for alarm system**

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore June 2015 - October 2015

- In this application to stop the alarm, the user has to solve either a mathematical puzzle or a logical puzzle or count the number of objects in the image or click the given color in the grid of colors. These functionalities are provided along with traditional alarm functionalities
- Github: https://github.com/praveensankar/Alarm-App

#### Face Recognition system using Principal Component Analysis

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore

- June 2014 October 2014
  - To detect and recognize an image from a predefined collection of images using the eigenface-based facial recognition
  - Github: https://github.com/praveensankar/face\_recognition

# **Teaching**

#### 1. Teaching Assistant - CS609 Network Programming Lab

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal August 2019 - November 2019

#### 2. Teaching Assistant - CS102 Basics of Programming Lab

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal January 2019 - April 2019

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: C, Python, SQL

**Operating Systems:** Ubuntu, Windows

Frameworks: Django

Tools: Latex

#### **Achievements**

• Scored 96.03 Percentile in Computer Science, GATE 2018

- Scored 98.02% in HSC exam, 2012
- Scored Centum in Computer Science, HSC exam, 2012
- Scored 97.80% in SSLC exam, 2010
- Scored Centum in Maths and Science, SSLC exam, 2010

# References

- 1. Dr. G. Aghila, Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the National Institute of Technology Puducherry, India. **Email**: aghila@nitpy.ac.in
- 2. Dr. R. Dhanalakshmi, Associate Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the Indian Institute of Information Technology Tiruchirapalli, India. **Email:** dhanalakshmiparthiban@gmail.com
- 3. Dr. P. Arun Raj Kumar, Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the National Institute of Technology Calicut, India. **Email:** park@nitc.ac.in